icmarkets.com 2019-04-07

# Australian Foreign Exchange Broker

## The Information we Collect

Here at International Capital Markets Pty Ltd (IC Markets) we care about your privacy. The purpose of our Privacy Policy is to describe to you what data we collect, how we collect it, and how and why we use your personal data. It also describes options for you to access, modify, delete or otherwise control the personal data that we have collected on you.

Personal data is information or an opinion relating to an individual, which can be used to identify that individual. In order to maintain our status as the world’s largest true ECN broker, it is important that we collect personal data from you in order to meet our legal obligations.

Your personal data may be collected via a number of methods not limited to but including account application forms, live chat, newsletters, seminars or over the telephone. Whenever it is reasonable and practicable to do so, we only collect information about you, directly from you.

  * Name, address, telephone number;
  * Email address;
  * Financial information;
  * Investment experience; 
  * Data that could indirectly or directly identify you;
  * and Other related information.

If at any time you have a question about our privacy policy or practices in general, you may reach our Data Protection Officer (“DPO”) at [compliance@icmarkets.com.au](mailto:compliance@icmarkets.com.au)

  * Provide you quality products or services;
  * Keep updated contact details.
  * Consider applications and approaches you make to us; and

  * The products and services we provide or have provided to you;
  * Your financial interests and sometimes your financial position; and
  * Your contact details

Sensitive information relating to your racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religion, trade union or other professional or trade association membership, sexual preferences and criminal record will not be collected without authorised consent you, or unless the collection is authorised by law.

## Personal Data

Much of what you likely consider personal data is collected directly from you when you:

1\. Create an account or use any of our services (example: name, address, credit card number, government identification number);

2\. Request assistance from our customer support team (example: phone number);

3\. Complete contact forms or request newsletters or other information from us (example: email); Or

4\. Otherwise participate in activities we promote that might require information about you (example: surveys, contests etc).

However, in delivering our services we may also collect additional information from you. This is to ensure that we can continue to provide top-quality performance to you, our client.

The way that we may collect additional information from you may not be obvious, as such, we wanted to highlight and explain what this could be and how and why it could be collected.

**1) Account related information:** this is information that is collected from you when you use our service. This could include your account number, trading history, correspondence with our Support Team and notes or details explaining what you asked for and how we responded.

**2) Cookies and similar technologies on our websites and our mobile applications:** this allow us to track your browsing behaviour on our website or other sites operated for or by IC Markets including our social media pages, your device type, and to collect various data, including analytics, about how you use and interact with our Services. By collecting and analysing this information we can better improve the performance our service. This allows us to provide you with more relevant product offerings and an overall better experience on our sites and mobile applications. We may also collect your IP address in order to better tailor your experience. Please see our cookie policy for more information.

**3) Data about Usage of Services:** this is automatically collected when you use and engage with our services, and can include metadata, log files, cookie/device IDs and location information. This information can include specific data about your interactions with our services, content and links (including those of third-parties, such as social media plugins), IP address, browser type and settings, the date and time the services were used, language preferences and cookie data, information about devices accessing the services (such as type of device, what operating system is used etc), and some of this data collected may be capable of and be used to approximate your location.

**4) Supplemented Data:** this may be received about you from other sources, including publicly available databases or third parties from whom we have purchased data from. However, if you provide us personal information about others, or if others give us your information, we will only use that information for the specific reason for which it was provided to us.

We do not sell personal information to other organisations. We may disclose personal information to service providers who provide services in connection with our products and services or we may provide information about you to your nominated financial adviser with your explicit permission. These third parties are subject to strict data processing terms and conditions which prohibit them from storing, sharing or utilising your personal data for any other purpose that for what they have been specifically contracted for.

## Keeping Information Accurate and Up to Date

We take all reasonable steps to ensure that all information we hold is as accurate as is possible. You are able to contact us at any time and ask for its correction if you feel the information we have about you is inaccurate or incomplete.

If you ask us, we will confirm whether we are processing your personal information, and, if so provide you with a copy of that personal information for free.

You may also view and update your account details and subscription preferences with respect to receiving communications from us, by logging in and visiting your “Account Details” page.

The information is provided in good faith and has been derived from sources believed to be reliable and accurate at the date indicated. IC Markets, its related bodies corporate or the directors or officers of those entities do not make any representation or warranty of reliability, completeness, fitness for purpose or accuracy of the information or any third-party website linked to IC Markets.

If you use the information, you do so at your own risk and you should consult IC Markets as to whether or not more recent information is available which will affect your investment decision.

## Keeping Information Secure

We use security procedures and the latest technology to protect the information we hold. Access to and use of personal information within IC Markets is appropriately limited to prevent misuse or unlawful disclosure of the information.

IC Markets will undertake to delete all personal information about an individual when it is no longer needed or required by law to be kept. We also destroy or de-identify all unsolicited personal information, unless we are authorised by law to store it.

Here are some of the way IC Market’s ensure your information is kept securely:

**1) Third Parties.** All contractors, sub-contractors, vendors, service providers, customers, agents or any other third parties that have access to personal information collected by IC Markets are required to have adequate privacy safeguards and must abide by this Privacy Policy. The third parties specifically agree to only use personal information for the purposes consented to by IC Markets or by the individual concerned.

**2) Transfer of personal data abroad.** If you utilize our services from a country other than the country where our servers are located, your communications with us may result in transferring your personal data across international borders. Also, when you call us or initiate a chat, we may provide you with support from outside your country of origin. This could be from either our head office in Australia or to an affiliate company located in another country, such as, our affiliate office in Cyprus. In these cases, your personal data is handled according to this Privacy Policy.

**3) Compliance with legal, regulatory and law enforcement requests.** We cooperate with government and law enforcement officials and private parties to enforce and comply with the law. We will disclose any information about you to government officials or private parties as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate to respond to claims and legal processes, to protect our property and rights or the property and rights of a third party, to protect the safety of the public or any person, or to prevent or stop activity we consider to be illegal or unethical.

In order to comply with ASIC rules and regulations we may have to share your information. However, we will take reasonable steps to notify you in the event that we are required to provide your personal information to third parties as part of a legal process.

**4) Website analytics:** we use multiple web analytics tools provided by service partners such as Google Analytics and Pingdom to collect information about how you interact with our website or mobile applications, including what pages you visit, what site you visited prior to visiting our website, how much time you spend on each page, what operating system and web browser you use and network and IP information. These tools will place cookies in your browser that can be used to identify you the next time you visit our website. We use this information to improve our services.

Each cookie can only be used by the service provider (example: Google for Google Analytics) and will not be used by anyone else. The information collected from the cookie may be transmitted to and stored by these service providers on servers in a country other than the country in which you reside. However, the information collected does not include data such as name, address, billing information, etc. The information collected is used and shared by these service providers in accordance with their individual privacy policies. You can control the technologies we use by managing your settings through our Cookie Policy or the ‘cookie banners” that may be presented to you when visiting our website.

**5) Targeted advertisements.** Targeted ads or interest-based offers may be presented to you based on your activities on our webpages, and other websites, and based on the products you currently own. These offers will display as varying product banners presented to you while browsing. We also partner with third parties to manage our advertising on our webpages and other websites. Our third-party partners may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about such activities in order to provide you with advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests, and to measure advertising effectiveness. If you wish to opt out of interest-based advertising, please go to your Account Details page or click the “Unsubscribe” button from the email sent. Please note you will continue to receive generic ads and important information and updates.

## Our Cookie Policy

As you browse our website www.icmarkets.com, advertising & campaign tracking cookies will be placed on your computer so that we can understand what you are interested in. Our display advertising partners include Google Adwords, Facebook, Taboola, Twitter, Bing-Yahoo networks etc. which enables us to present you with retargeting advertising on other sites based on your previous interaction with our website. The techniques our partners employ do not allow them to collect personal information such as your name, email address, postal address, or telephone number.

## How You Can Access, Update Or Delete Your Personal Data

In order to easily access your personal data please sign into your Account and visit “Account Details”. From here you can view, update or delete (where available), and update your subscription preferences. Please contact our Support Team for additional information and guidance for accessing, updating or deleting data.

If you make a request to delete your personal data and that data is necessary for the products or services you have purchased, the request will be honoured only to the extent it is no longer necessary for any services purchased or required for our legitimate business purposes or legal or contractual record keeping requirements.

Furthermore, you can contact us to request access to any other personal data stored on you that is not readily available in your “Account Settings”. In normal circumstances we will give you full access to your information. However, there may be some legal or administrative reasons to deny access. If access is denied, we will provide you with the reason why.

## How We Communicate With You

We may contact you directly or through a third party service provider such as necessary to deliver transactional or service related communications. We may also contact you with offers for additional services we think you’ll find valuable if you give us consent, or where allowed based upon legitimate interests. You don’t need to provide consent as a condition to purchase our goods or services. These contacts may include:

  * Email
  * Text (SMS) messages
  * Telephone calls
  * Automated phone calls or text messages.

You may also update your subscription preferences with respect to receiving communications from us and/or our partners by signing into your account and visiting “Account Settings” page.

If you believe that anyone has provided us with your personal information and you would like to request that it be removed from our database, please contact our Support Team.

## Changes in our Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time. When we make any modifications to our Privacy Policy, we will notify you and/or put a notification in a place on our website that we find appropriate. This is so you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, that we disclose it.

## Contact Us

If you have any questions, concerns or complaints about our Privacy Policy, our practices or our Services, you may contact our DPO by email a [compliance@icmarkets.com.au](mailto:compliance@icmarkets.com.au)

In the alternative, you may contact us at:

International Capital Markets Pty Ltd

Level 6 309 Kent Street

Sydney NSW

2000 AUSTRALIA

Email : [info@icmarkets.com](mailto:info@icmarkets.com)

**Phone: :** +61 (0)2 8014 4280
